Mike Hageali

1895 S. Morrison Ln. Gilbert, Arizona (480)457-9981 zmanphx2000@yahoo.com

About Me

I have been successfully involved in software and database development in my career for over 20 years. Being a database and object-oriented programmer, I have acquired analytical and logical skills to translate business needs and workflows to create programmed solutions. I am always looking for new challenges and to learn new things. I have decided to do a mid-career change and immerse myself into the web development world. I decided to enroll in professional training boot camp for full stack web development.

Technical Skills

- MicroSoft SQL scripting, stored procedures, SQL Agent
- HL7 Developer (EDI) Orion Software, HL7 ADTs
- C# Visual Studio .Net, Visual Basic .Net
- Visual Studio, Team Management source control
- Program design and logic flow
- Project Management and consulting
- Technical Solutions requirements analysis
- Documentation writing
- Project proposal quoting and writing
- HTML, CSS, Java, Javasript, Jquery
- HTML Dom manipulations
- Web api, ajax, JSON objects
- Git Hub source control code repository

Experience

LVM Systems - Data Team Integrations

Mesa, Arizona: February 2015-October 2018

- Customized Solutions in Visual Studio .Net, SQL databases
- HL7 Developer integrating Epic, Cerner, Star, Touchworks
- Developed C# reports and record migration from external systems
- Managed client supported trouble-shooting and exception issues

- Trained and mentored junior level developers with code and scripting
- Managed and created new project proposals

McKesson RelayHealth - Client Development Support

Scottsdale, Arizona: June 2001- February 2015

- Customized programming, support of client interfaces Visual Studio
 .Net, SQL databases
- HL7 Developer integrating Epic, Cerner, Star, Touchworks, All Scripts systems
- Developed data real-time communications link using HL7 TCP/IP HL7 protocols
- Developed SQL stored procedures scripting solutions
- Provided consultative services on technical issues to clients and internal project teams.
- Trained operations personal on their support roles for application software
- Managed and created new project proposals for client specifications
- Write technical documentation and proposals for service offerings
- Developed new healthcare transaction flow to meet federal government reporting requirements

Schaller Anderson - Medicare Billing Reports

Phoenix, Arizona: Oct. 1999- June 2001

- Customized Crystal Reports development
- SQL database scripting using custom views
- Developed **Visual Basic** data SQL extractions for statistical reports

World Com Wireless - Contractor Developer

Phoenix, Arizona: Jan 1998- Oct. 1999

- Developed billing logic for cell phone plans
- Programmed monthly promotions plans

Education

University of Arizona Coding Boot Camp

Gilbert, Arizona: July 2019

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Express.js
- React.js
- Node.js
- Database Theory
- MongoDB, MySQL
- Command Line
- Java
- Git
- API/ JSON

Brigham Young University

Provo, Utah: May 1995

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Core Emphasis: Information Systems (IS)

- Relational Database Design
- Database Normalization
- SQL Scripting
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Electronic Data Interchange (EDI)

External Links

View my Git code repository and Linkedin Profile